# SHUBHAM SHUKLA

905-869-3268 • ishubham326@gmail.com • github.com/ishubham326

# HIGHLIGHTS OF QUALIFICAIONS

- Enrolled in 4<sup>th</sup> year of Computer Engineering CO-OP program at McMaster University. Graduating 2022.
- Proficient in React, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Material UI and SASS through self-learning, projects, and schoolwork.
  Currently expanding my skills on Redux and, MangoDB. I also have experience in Python, C++, PHP through Uni projects and WordPress from free-lance work. Currently working towards building my skills for front end web development through online courses outside of university, personal projects as well as freeCodeCamp.
- Experienced in UI design, video and photo editing using the Adobe suite (Premier Pro, Photoshop, Lightroom and XD).
- Excellent problem solving and technical skills. Quick adaptive learning developed through not only programming, but also constant adaptation of new hobbies and skills.
- Strong **communication**, **leadership**, **and management skills** through volunteering, being a free-lance logo designer, photographer, musician, and editor.

## **EXPERIENCE**

NOV 2021 - CURRENT

## **JR. FRONT-END WEB DEV - PLANT8**

- Using React to develop new production level platform previously based on Laravel
- Responsible for test driven development, and edge to edge testing
- Responsible for implementing features, bug fixes, clean up code base and optimizing UI/UX experience

MAY 2021 - AUGUST 2021

## FRONT-END WEB DEV AND ECOMMERCE INTERN - 3D POWDER HUB

- Designed, implemented, and managed www.3dpowderhub.com using WordPress.
- Responsible for implementing custom features using PHP and CSS
- Responsible for creating custom graphics, email templates and any other design orientated tasks

## SEPT 2019 - AUGUST 2020

#### RESEARCH INTERN/WEBSITE MANAGEMENT - CNEM CORPORATION

- Designed, implemented, and managed company website under the domains <u>www.cnemcorp.com</u>, and <u>3denginearrings.com</u>/ with WordPress.
- Implemented custom styling with CSS and functionality using PHP.
- Worked on a metal foam project for renewable energy, electronics, and environmental applications (Heat pipes and vapor chambers using copper foam). Property testing, product processing, and optimization.
- Studied the effects of metal foam geometry on heat transfer behaviors and performed daily lab assignments and efficiently recorded test results.

### AUG 2018

### **CODING TEACHER VOLUNTEER - MCMASTER UNIVERSITY**

- Performed programming workshop teaching basic coding skills to first year Biomed and a couple other engineering streams students.
- Helped answer questions regarding their future paths.
- Overlooked and helped run a mini course that included concepts from Python, C89, and Basic Arduino/Raspberry Pi skills.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **EXPECTED GRADUATION 2022**

## **BACHELOR'S IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING - MCMASTER UNIVERSITY**

- The degree itself consists of many classes ranging from coding to hardware knowledge with a high quantity of work and responsibilities.
- Worked on projects and courses that included learning C, C++, Python, Verilog, and JS.
- Projects include pacemakers, RC car using UARTS & FMUs, image processing, machine learning, and an autonomous chessboard

## FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPMENT - FREE CODE CAMP

- Self-teaching myself everything I can about front-end web development while doing my undergrad at McMaster. I am expanding my skills upon UI/UX design, web design and graphic design, allowing me to design well-made websites. My goal is to adapt full stack development later in my life but only after I have a strong on front end.
- HTML/CSS Certification and Vanilla JavaScript Certification Complete Certificate Link

# FAVOURITE PROJECTS - AVAILABLE ON GITHUB

## TRAVEL ADVISOR - REACT

- Uses React and Material UI
- Uses Google Maps API, Travel Advisor & Weather API

## **TENZIES - REACT**

- Mini game using React and custom CSS styling
- Focuses on state management

### **GET WORK DONE**

- Multiple apps in one, using jQuery, Vanilla JS
- To-do list, minesweeper, rock paper scissors, countdown and pomodoro timer

## PICK A COLOR (COLOR PALETTE PICKER)

- Uses Vanilla JS
- Responsive web design

## **SHRI MAHA LAXMI**

- Uses HTML, SASS, Vanilla JS
- Responsive Web Design
- Custom Graphics

# freeCodeCamp PROJECTS

- Projects range from HTML, CSS, jQuery, Vanilla JS, React, Redux and more.
- All include the FCC string in their title

Please feel free to check out the rest on my GitHub page.